Clemens Fiedler

website: clemensfiedler.com | email: clemens.mb.fiedler@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/clemensfiedler | nationality: Austrian

Profile

Curious and problem-oriented researcher with an extensive background in **Economics**, **Data Science**, and **Competition Policy**; highly skilled in **Python** and **R** and active **teacher of programming**. Well versed to understand both both **Game Theoretical** and **Data Science** models. A versatile, motivated, and experienced **leader**, **coordinator**, and **team worker** willing to take the initiative and engage problems head-on.

Work Experience

Researcher Data Science & Financial Markets, CPB Netherlands Bureau for Economic Policy Analysis

October 2019 -Currently

- Using cutting-edge Data Science models to study economic and sociopolitical issues.
- Experimenting, applying, and evaluating of Machine Learning methods.
- Organizing courses and disseminate of Data Science knowledge.

External Lecturer Tilburg University,

January 2020 -Currently

- Teaching M.Sc. Course on Competition Policy.
- Supervising M.Sc. Thesis on Data Science and Machine Learning.

Ph.D. Candidate in Economics, Tilburg University

Supervisors: Prof. Jan Boone, Dr. Florian Schütt

September 2015 -September 2019

- Extensive experiences with presenting to academic and professional audience within and outside of my field.
- Detailed knowledge of the challenges of competition policy in high-tech and software markets.
- Deep understanding of game theoretical and microeconomical models, computational simulations, and econometric methods.
- Experience as teacher in course on competition policy and programming at Bachelor's and Master's level.

Education

Ph.D. in Economics, Tilburg University Innovation in the Digital Age: Competition, Cooperation and Standardization	September 2015 - October 2020
M.Sc. (Research Master) in Economics, Tilburg University Cum Laude, Major: Microeconomic Theory, Minor: Econometrics.	August 2013 - September 2015
M.Sc. in Economics, Vienna University of Business and Economics With Distinction, Major: Mathematics.	August 2011 - July 2013

B.Sc. in Business, Economics and Social Sciences Vienna University of Business and Economics

September 2006 -March 2011

Extracurricular Activities

Board Member, Tilburg Ph.D. Platform, Tilburg University

- Represented the interests of Ph.D. candidates within the university.
- Facilitated information sharing between schools and management.
- Organized courses on programming for Ph.D. Candidates and Faculty.

Founder & Organizer, Programming Group, Tilburg University

- Founded the cross-disciplinary TiSEM Programming Group.
- Set up the infrastructure and developed the strategic plan.
- Invited lecturers and coordinated seminar schedule.

September 2017 -July 2019

September 2017 - February 2019

Council Member, Faculty Council (TiSEM), Tilburg University

- Represented the interests of Ph.D. candidates within the Faculty.
- Advised management team, discussed and approved policy and budget.

March 2017 -September 2018

Chairman, Graduate Students' Society, Tilburg University

- Planned activities of the GSS and developed the strategic plan.
- Conducted meetings with stakeholders of the Graduate School.
- Coordinated between the different members of the GSS board.

IT Coordinator, Graduate Students' Society, Tilburg University

August 2014 -September 2016

September 2018

Skills

Lanuages:

English (fluent), German (native), Dutch (proficient)

Programming and Econometrics:

Python (fluent), R (fluent), Mathematica (proficient), Stata (proficient)

Collabaration:

Git, Latex, MS Office

Interests & Activities

Professional Interests:

Competition Policy, Data Science, and Financial Markets

Personal Interests:

Programming, Riddles, Technology, Physics, and Science Fiction

Other Activities:

Running, Cycling, Swimming, Strategy Games

terriber 2010

lune 2016 -